자막제작 - 네이트 CSI 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/clubcsi)
잘 오셨어요
Welcome.
축하하네, 패트릭
Congratulations, Patrick.
감사합니다, 서장님
Well, thank you, Sheriff.
오늘 밤 참석해 주셔서
정말 기쁩니다
Your presence here means to me a lot tonight.
저 말씀인가요?
Is that for me?
잔을 말씀하는 건가요?
아니면 샴페인?
Are you talking about the glass or the bubbly?
얼굴의 미소를 말하는 건데요
I was talking about the smile on your face.
제가 웃고 있다면 160만
달러의 모금액 때문이겠죠
Well, if I'm smiling, it's because we've
raised one point six million dollars
리치몬드 부인의 화상 센터를
위한 자선파티에서요
for Mrs. Richmond's Burn Center tonight.
후한 마음 씀씀이에
감사하며 건배하죠
That sort of generosity
deserves a raise of the glass.
포셔를 위해
To Portia.
오늘 밤 그녀가
없어서 아쉽네요
It's a shame she couldn't be here tonight.
실례합니다
Excuse me.
우리가 해냈어
Hey, we did it.
그래 해냈어
We sure did.
실례할게요
Excuse me.
서장님, 턱시도 멋지네요
Nice tux, Sheriff.
여기가 누구 집인지 자네 아나?
You know whose house this is?
라스베가스에 살려면 유명인사와
그들 이력 정도는 알아야죠
To know this town is to know
it's celebrities, and their histories.
포셔 리치몬드는 전성기 때
전설적인 쇼걸이었죠
Portia Richmond was
a legendary showgirl in her day.
저 여자 포셔 리치몬드는 아니군요
But that's not her.
아마 30년 전쯤, 그녀가 리도 쇼의
주연이었을 때는 저랬을지도 모르지
Maybe thirty years ago, when she was
the headliner in the Lido de Paris.
누가 발견했죠?
Who found her?
주위를 둘러보게나
Look around you.
밤새 걸리겠군
This is going to take all night.
전채요리나 들면서
Come for the hors d'oeuvres,
심문을 위해 기다려 달라고 해야죠
stay for the interrogation.
CSI: Crime Scene Investigation
1x15 Table Stakes
월리암 피터슨(길 그리섬役)
CSI 레벨 3(반장), 전문분야 : 곤충학
마그 헬겐버거(캐서린 윌로우스役)
CSI 레벨 3, 전문분야 : 혈흔 분석
게리 도단(워릭 브라운役)
CSI 레벨 3, 전문분야 : 음향/시각 자료분석
조지 이즈(닉 스톡스役)
CSI 레벨 3, 전문분야 : 머리카락, 섬유질 분석
조자 폭스(새라 사이들役)
CSI 레벨 3, 전문분야 : 물질성분 분석
폴 길포일(짐 브래스役)
라스베가스 시경
싱크 편집
송미혜(smh8119@nate.com)
한글 번역
주동권(ozsotr@hotmail.com)
ORIGINAL AIR DATE ON CBS: 2001/02/22
네, 최선을 다하겠습니다
Yes sir, I'll do my best.
내가 전화에서 말했던 것처럼
Alright, you guys, like I said on the phone,
큰 파티고 아주 큰 집이니까
it's a big party and it's a huge big house
나누어서 일을 처리하도록 하지
so were gonna divide and conquer.
닉 자넨 전반적으로 둘러보고
Nick, tonight, you do
the overall sketch. Alright?
캐서린과 워릭은
수영장 쪽을 맡아주게
Catherine and Warrick,
you got the pool area.
내가 얕은 쪽을 맡을게
I'll take the shallow end.
그렇다면 전 깊은 쪽을 ….
Guess, I'm going deep.
이런 물고기에게 밥을
주려면 얼마나 들까요?
I wonder how much it costs
to feed all these fish?
네
Right.
마르코!
Marco!
폴로!
Polo.
손님, 수영장에서 나와 주시겠어요
해가 지면 수영장은 닫거든요
Wanna get out of there sir.
Pool closes at sundown.
손님, 수건 가져다 드릴까요?
Can I get you a towel, sir?
네, 부탁해요
Yeah, please.
뭘 찾았나?
What did you find?
커프스단추 같은 거네요
Looks like a cufflink.
CM이란 이니셜이 있네요
Initial's, "CM."
하늘색과 은색이입니다
Turquoise and silver.
아마 남서부에서
온 거 같네요
Breaks down the regionality
to the southwest maybe.
애리조나, 뉴멕시코
텍사스 같은데요
Arizona, New Mexico, Texas.
멋진 걸 찾았군, 친구
Good catch, Pal.
손님 리스트를 받아서
CM을 체크해보게
You get the guest list. Check for CM's.
밤새 젖어있겠군
I'm going to be wet all night.
알칼로이드의 쓴 냄새가 나네요
(커피 냄새가 난다는 말)
I detect a bitter of alkaloid.
아무에게도 이 사실을 말하면
안 되네. ‘마키아토’야
Don't tell anybody my weakness,
one macchiato tall.
시 예산으로 구입하신
커피메이커인 것 같네요
Coffee machine courtesy
of the city I presume.
검시관이 요구하면
왜 필요한지 묻지도 않지
When the coronor asks for something
they don't question it.
맛있게 마실게요 / 그래
Cheers. / Cheers.
이리 와보게
Come on.
신원을 밝히셨어요?
Have we I.D.'d her yet?
아직 살펴보고 있네
Working on it.
성형수술을 했더군
She's had a few upgrades.
얼굴 윤곽을 새로 잡았고
코 성형을 했어
Submalar augmentation. Rhinoplasty.
가슴엔 실리콘을 넣었어
Silicone breasts.
삽입물의 일련번호를 확인하면
바로 누군지 알 수 있겠군요
Run the serial number on the implants.
Instant i.d.
이 분야가 많이 발전했지
그렇지 않은가?
Our field's come a long way, hasn't it?
이쪽에 상처가 집중됐더군
We got a whole menu here.
점상출혈과 목 주위에 멍이 들고
목뿔뼈(설골)가 부러졌네
Petichial hemorrhaging, bruising around
the neck and broken hyoid bone.
목이 졸린 거군요
She was strangled.
폐에 물이 없는 걸로 봐서
No water in the lungs.
죽은 다음에 물에 빠진 것 같네
But she was dead before she hit the water.
교살은 주로 남성이 저지르는
범죄 양상이죠
Strangulation's a man's crime.
하산해도 되겠군
Preaching to the converted.
박사님, 상처 주위 사진도 찍으시고
성폭력 당했는지도 확인해 주세요
Do me a favor, Doc. Photograph her
injuries and run a sexual assault kit.
경막하에 난 멍도
적외선 검사해 주시고요
Include infrared for subdural bruising.
이건 자네와 나만
아는 걸로 하세
This is our little secret.
이봐 / 네
Hey / Hey
스피어 호텔 전망용 엘리베이터에
변사체가 발견됐어. 자네가 맡아줘
419 at The Sphere,
glass elevator. You're on it.
이건 큰 사건이잖아요
This is a big case.
제 말씀은 제가 여기에
있어야하는 거 아니냐는 겁니다
I mean I'm in a groove here.
글쎄, 시내에 가서
재능을 발휘해봐
Well, groove on down to the Strip.
무슨 일이든지 한 번 시작하면
끝까지 하라고 그러셨잖아요?
Whatever happened to
'you cross the tape, you go the distance?'
아마 그때는 내가 자네
도움이 필요했었겠지
I was probably saying that to get you
to service my needs at the time.
여보세요 / 그렇군요
Hello? / Great.
새라, 자고 있어? / 네
Hey, Sara, you sleeping? /Yeah.
잠시 실례
Excuse me for a minute.
내가 여기 있는 사람들에게 물어봤더니
I got the horsepower on everybody here.
백이면 백, 아무것도
못 봤거나 모른다고 그러네
Ninety-nine percent of the people,
know nothing, saw nothing.
놀라운 일이지
Big surprise.
포셔 리치몬드는 이야기는 없어요?
What about Portia Richmond?
글쎄, 그 사람 친구들은 포셔가
Well, according to her friends, uh,
아주 ‘싱싱한’ 젊은 남자와
한 달 정도 사귀고 있다더군
she's been romancing some
young stallion for over a month.
사랑에 빠져 지중해 상 어떤
요트 위에서 마약에 절어있겠지
She's in love. She's cruising the Mediterranean
on some yacht. Eating cheese cubes.
그 커플에게 집을
맡겨두고 말이야
Got a couple watching the house.
종종 집을 비우는 것 같아
Apparently, she often takes in strays.
헤인즈 씨, 길 그리섬이고
캐서린 윌로우스입니다
Mr. and Mrs. Haynes, this is
Gil Grissom and Catherine Willows.
과학수사대에서 나왔습니다
They're from the Crime Lab.
안녕하세요
Hi.
몇 가지 더 여쭤봐도
되겠습니까?
Do you mind if we ask you
a few more questions?
그럼요
By all means.
어떻게 포셔 리치몬드 씨를
알게 됐나요?
How is it that that you know Portia Richmond?
지중해 호텔 꼭대기에 있는
모라도 클럽에서 처음 봤어요
Oh, we, we met her at the Morado
at the top of The Mediterranean.
거기 가려면 뒷마당에 유전이라도
있어야 한다는 거 같던데..
You need an oil well in your backyard
to belong to that place.
프라이빗 클럽이죠. 가입하는 데만
연 5만 달러는 내야하죠
Private club. Fifty grand a year
just to walk through the door.
그렇지만 그만한 값어친 하죠
But worth every penny.
우리에게 포셔는 매우
친숙한 사람이었어요
It was like we'd known Portia all our lives.
그런 느낌 받아본 적 있나요?
Has that ever happen to you?
아니요
No.
우린 여기 신출내기였죠
We were new in town.
포셔가 우릴 주위에 소개시켜줬죠
우릴 보살펴 준거죠
Portia introduced us around.
Took us under her wing.
우린 후진 동부 출신으로
서로 아는 사이입니다
We're from back East.
We have mutual acquaintances.
그럼 집을 봐주는 겁니까?
And you're house-sitting?
아님 여기가 주소지입니까?
Or you're living in?
잠시 더부살이하는 거죠
살 집을 찾을 때까지요
House-sitting, while
hunting for our own place.
포셔는 우리한테 돈도
받으려 하지 않았지요
Portia refused to take any money from us.
심지어 저녁 식사도
다 그녀가 샀어요
She wouldn't even let us pay for a dinner.
그게 그녀가 유럽에 간 다음에
That's why when she took off to Europe...
이 자선 행사를 연 이유예요
... we offered to host this charity event.
우리가 할 수 있는
최소한의 것이었죠
It's the least we could do.
우린 파티를 여는 것쯤은 아니까요
After all, we know how to throw a party.
맞는 말씀이네요
You can say that again.
죽은 여자에 대해 아시나요?
Did you know the deceased woman?
아뇨
No.
그럼 부인은요?
And you miss?
제가 알기로는 그 여자
초대 손님 명단에도 없다더군요
As far as I know, she wasn't
even on the guest list.
뭐가 잘못 됐나요?
Something wrong?
네. 한 여자가 죽었죠
Yes. A woman's dead.
레이시 듀발이 살해됐다고?
Lacey Duvall murdered.
어제 밤까지만 해도
여기에 있었는데...
She was here last night.
믿을 수 없군요
Unbelievable.
그녀와 가까웠던 사람을
만날 수 있을까요?
Could you put us in touch with
someone who was close to her?
물론. 레이첼 카슨이라고
둘이 가까운 친구였소
Sure. Rachel Carson.
They were best friends.
자매처럼 말이오
Like sisters.
대기실에 있을 거니 따라 오시오
She's in back. Follow me.
입 좀 다무시죠
Close your mouth.
레이시는 어떤 돈 많은
유부남을 만나고 있었죠
She was seeing some rich married guy.
이름은 아시나요?
Have a name?
아뇨. 이름을 말하지
않으려 했어요
Yeah, but she wouldn't tell me.
근데 있잖아요
정말로 이상했어요
You know, that's the thing...
it was so weird...
그 남자는 레이첼에게 자신에 관한
어떤 것도 말하지 않으려 했어요
He refused to tell her anything
about himself... anything.
전 이상한 느낌이 든다고 말했었는데
레이시가 죽었다니
I told her it gave me the creeps, but
you couldn't talk to her. You know?
미스터리와 섹스 때문에
Turned on by the mystery and the sex.
제가 현장에 있었던 거죠
I've been there.
실례해요
Hi
도와드릴까요?
Do you need a hand with that?
아... 아니에요. 괜찮습니다
Oh, no, thanks. I'll be fine.
의사신가요?
Are you a doctor?
뭐 비슷하죠
Of sorts.
전 그냥...
둘러보고 있습니다
I'm just um, looking around.
뭐 특별한 거라도 발견했나요?
See anything you like?
네. 그랬죠
Yes. I do.
캐서린!
Catherine!
차이코프스키의
'꽃을 위한 왈츠'야
Tchaikovsky's "Waltz of the Flowers."
그 웃음은 뭐죠?
What's with the smile?
내 사랑 포셔, 당신의 남편, 1969.3.7
우리를 위해 노래를 부르고 있군
It's playing our song.
콘로이 형사님
Detective Conroy.
무슨 일이야?
큰 사건에서 밀려 나온 거야?
What happened? You get
bumped from First Class?
아뇨. 전 혼자 일할 때
진가를 발휘하죠
No. I do my best work solo.
제시간에 맞추어서 말이죠
On the clock, that is.
무슨 사건이죠
What've you got?
평범한 장소에서 아주 대담하게
범행을 저질렀어
Walk-through in plain site.
Risky move.
과녁 가장자리만 노려서 쐈군요
한 발은 눈 사이에 맞았고요
All around the ten ring,
once between the eyes.
사입구를 보니 어떤 생각이 듭니까?
소구경 총이 아닐까요?
Entry wound give you anything?
Small caliber?
혼자 일하는 게 좋다며
You like to work solo.
직접 살펴봐
Take a look for yourself.
어떤 것 같아?
Any thoughts?
전문가 솜씨예요
Professional hit.
저, 닉스가 어땠죠?
Hey, well, how did the Knicks make out?
너보단 잘 했지
Better than you.
카나리아 시절 이후로
시대가 많이 변하긴 했죠?
Times have changed since
the canary days. Huh?
카나리아 시절이라고?
Canary days?
그래요. 브래스 경감님이 마피아가
살인을 할 때의 이야기를 해주셨는데
Yeah, Brass used to tell me back in the day
when the Mob would make a hit,
그 마피아는 카나리아가
노래를 부르게 두고 간다더군요
he'd leave a canary,
'cause the guy sang.
그럼 25센트 동전은
뭘 뜻하는 거야?
And the quarter stands for?
‘아는 사람에게 연락하라’
"Call somebody who cares."
잡히기를 바라는 사람 같군
It's almost like the guy wants to get caught.
의도적으로 총을 남겨두었을 땐
아무것도 안 나온다는 말이죠
When you leave a gun you know it's clean.
이 총에선 아무것도
안 나올 거예요
The gun just traces back to itself.
살인자가 꽤나 널 힘들게 하는군
그럼 이제 어떻게 할 텐가?
The killer cut you off at the knees.
So what are you going to do?
할 수 있는 뭐든지 해야죠
All I can do
정해진 일의 순서에 따라서요
follow protocol.
엘리베이터 전체에서
지문을 뜰 텐가?
You're gonna print the entire elevator?
금요일 밤의 바에서처럼...
Like the Circle Bar on a Friday night
수많은 사람들이 지문이
겹쳐 나오겠죠
three million people on top of each other.
제가 맞혀보죠
Let me guess
왜 레이스 듀발이 포셔 리치몬드 이름이
새겨진 음악상자를 갖고 있는지 고민이죠?
You're wondering why Lacey Duvall
had a music box engraved to Portia Richmond.
그렇게 생각해?
You think?
서로 아는 사이여서 선물한
거라면 간단할 듯 한데요
Well, maybe it's as simple as
they knew each other, she gave it to her.
글쎄, 서로 아는 사이였다면
왜 초대 손님 명단에 없었을까?
Well, if they knew each other
why wasn't she on the guest list?
1969년 3월 7일
캐서린에게는 의미 있는 날이야?
March 7, 1969 mean anything to you?
리치몬드에게는 의미 있는 날이겠지
It meant something to the Richmonds.
에디와 제가 처음 결혼했을 때
아주 사이가 좋았을 때는
You know when Eddie and I were first married,
when things were kind of good,
우리가 첨 만난 날에, 에딘 항상
레이스 테디를 선물하곤 했죠
on the anniversary of the day we first met,
he always gave me a lace teddy.
어… 그래요
그게 음악상자는 아니죠
Well, I mean, I know
it's not a music box, but
음악상자나 레이스 테디
모두 같은 거야
Music box, lace teddy,
it's all the same thing.
그건 전통이거든
It's tradition.
전통의 즐거움은 항상
반복되는 데 있지
And the joy of tradition
is the constant repetition.
그렇군요
Right.
도대체 난 뭐지? 호텔에서 음식이나
음료수 나르는 사람인줄 아나?
What am I, working food and
beverage at one of the hotels.
글쎄 3주 동안
하루도 못 쉬었다니까
I haven't had a day off in three weeks.
나를 호출하려거든
그럴 만한 사건을 줘야지
If they're gonna call me in?
Throw me a bone.
나한테 엘리베이터의 변사체
사건을 줘야 하는 거 아냐?
Give me the 419 on the elevator.
- 다른 사람들이 싫어할 텐데
- 난 지쳤다고
- Someone's bitter.
- I'm tired.
너? 지쳤다고? 난 네가 잠도
안자고 일한다고 생각했는데
You? Tired?
I thought you never sleep.
좋아 좋아
Nice. Nice.
안녕, 그렉
What's up,dude?
좋아 보이네. 정말 싫군
You're awake. I hate you.
몇 잔의 메를로 와인과
양고기를 먹으면서 휴일을 보냈죠
Couple of glasses of Merlot.
Rack of lamb on my day off.
어젠 정말 아기처럼 잤다니까요
I slept like a baby yesterday.
상태가 안 좋아 보이네요
You look horrible.
고마워, 그렉
Thanks, Greg.
나는 아니야
난 밤새 일했다고
Don't look at me.
I got sunshine all night.
성폭력 검사와 손톱에서
나온 DNA를 조사해줘
Check for DNA in the sexual assault kit
and the fingernail, please.
최대한 빨리 CODIS에 넣어보고
Everything's has to be in CODIS A.S.A.P.
그게 전부예요? 그런데 제 연장근무는
누가 허가하는 거죠?
Oh. Is that all? I don't know...
who's going to authorize my overtime?
말이 많군, 그렉
벌써 푹 쉬었잖아
Suck it up, Greg. You're well rested.
새라 선배 한텐 발륨이 필요한 게 아녜요?
(Valium : 정신안정제, 상표명)
You want a Valium for her?
I heard that.
1973년 3월 7일
March 7, 1973.
1981년 3월 7일
March 7, 1981.
1956년 3월 7일
March 7, 1956.
1986년 3월 7일
March 7, 1986.
남편이 죽을 때까지
매년 기념일 마다 준 것 같군
I bet he gave her one every
anniversary until he died.
이것을 선물로 줘버린
것 같진 않아요
She wouldnt' give away
a gift this sentimental.
적어도 이건
'꽃을 위한 왈츠'는 아니네요
At least it's not "Waltz of the Flowers."
문의 봉인이 찢겨져
있지는 않았는데
The seal on the door wasn't broken.
라스베가스 경찰입니다
Las Vegas Police Department.
하다가 들켰네요
Caught in the act.
내 생각엔 그 점이
중요한 것 같군
I think that was the point.
아 그래요?
Oh yeah.
아냐, 나 더 이상
커피 못 마시겠어
No, I can't drink anymore coffee.
내 생체 시계가
완전히 망가진 듯 해
My body clock is so screwed up.
난 스테이크가 필요해
I just want a steak and a shot.
‘투탄카멘의 무덤’
계란 얹은 스테이크
Tuts Tomb. Steak and eggs.
1불 99센트에
Dollar ninety-nine.
음식 …?
Food.?
좋은 생각이야. 그래 좋아
Good idea. You're on.
이래서 제가 산다니까요
It's what I live for.
정말 믿지 못할 걸요?
준비 됐나요?
You're guys are never going to believe this.
You ready?
준비됐어
So much for the steak.
- 내가 그 커피 마셔도 될까?
- 그래
- I'll take that coffee?
- Yeah.
좋아요. 죽은 쇼걸인 레이스 듀발
성폭력 검사에서
Okay. Sexual assault kit on Lacey Duvall,
the dead showgirl,
정액에 대한 양성 반응이 나왔어요
came back positive for semen.
그런데... 그건 아무것도 아니에요
But... phrsst... that's nothing.
그걸 CODIS에 돌려봤는데, 발견된 DNA가
텍사스 미결사건의 DNA와 일치하더군요
Ran it through CODIS. Seminal DNA
matches a cold case from Texas
10년 전에 죽은
치어리더 사건이라고요
A dead cheerleader, 10 years ago.
- 일거양득이네
- 좋아. 이제 기군이 나는군
- Two for one. / - Okay. I'm up.
서장님, 이 사건에 네 명의
요원이 조사를 하고 있습니다
Sir, I have four criminalysts working on this.
그래, 뭔가 건졌나?
Well, don't you have anything, yet?
아뇨. 뭔가 알게 되면
바로 연락드리겠습니다
No, as soon as we find
something tangible I'll call you.
약속드립니다
I promise.
서장인가?
Sheriff?
네. 매시간 전화를 하는군요
아무것도 할 수가 없어요
Yeah, he calls me every hour.
I can't get anything done.
나한텐 30분마다 전화한다네
Every half for me.
놀라지 않으셨길 바랍니다
Hope we didn't embarrass you.
그 말을 하기엔
좀 늦은 듯하네요
Little late for that.
네, 안녕하시죠?
Yeah, uh hi.
제가 리치몬드 부인의 행방에 대해
좀 더 여쭤봐야 할 것 같군요
I just have a few more questions about
the whereabouts of Mrs. Richmond.
네, 말씀하세요
Fire away.
음료수 드실 분 없나요?
Drinks for anybody else?
아니요, 감사합니다
No thank you.
그럼 어…, 기본적인
질문을 하도록 하죠
So let's uh, let's just take baby steps.
그녀가 어디 있다고요?
Where is she?
그리스 제도 어딘가에
있는 요트에 있겠죠
On a yacht somewhere in the Greek Isles.
연락해야 할 일이 생기면
어떻게 하죠?
And if someone wanted to reach her?
나침반 가지고 계시나요?
You have a compass?
네
Yeah.
연락이 두절된 상태죠
She's incommunicado.
놀라운 말씀이네요
Big word.
저희가 무슨 잘못이라도
저질렀나요?
Have we done something wrong?
왜요?
What?
빨대를 제가 가져도 될까요?
May I have your straw?
제가 그걸 모으거든요
I, I collect them.
고맙습니다
Thank you.
주위를 둘러봐도 될까요?
Mind if I look around a little?
그러시죠
Have at it.
여주인의 침실이군
The hostess' bedroom.
아주 이상해
Too kinky.
포셔가 목욕 가운을
가져갔는지 한 번 보죠
Let me see if Portia took
the bathing suit with her.
여기 있네요
Here we go.
목욕 가운, 란제리
보석, 지갑, 가방
We got the bathingsuit.
Lingerie jewels, wallet, bags.
제가 생각하기엔 어디에
간 것 같지 않아요
I'm not so sure she's gone anywhere.
그럼 방도 조사해 볼까?
Shall we do the room too?
이의 요정이 우리에게 포셔 리치몬드의
치아를 남겨준 것 같군
I think the tooth fairy might have just
left us a piece of Portia Richmond.
네?
What?
한 번 봐
Take a look.
두 가지 사건이 되었군요
I guess now we have two cases.
살인자가 없는 사체와
사체 없는 살인
We got a body without a murderer.
And a murder without a body.
와, 이거 풀면 진급하겠어요
Oh man, I gotta get a raise for this.
그렉, 치아 DNA 분석표 작성해서
Greg, well, just start
the DNA profile on the tooth,
그게 포셔 리치몬드와
일치하는지 알아봐줘
so that we can tell if it's Portia Richmond.
음... 이 이에서 DNA를
검출하는 건 쉽겠죠
Yeah, well, getting DNA from
this tooth is gonna be easy.
하지만 그걸 뭐하고 비교하죠?
What am I supposed to compare it to?
그녀 집에서 가져온
칫솔이나 빗은 어때?
How about the toothbrush and
hairbrush we took from her vanity?
현미경을 한 번 보시겠어요?
Why don't you go talk to
the dead end twins over there.
여긴 아무것도 없네요
Nothing in here.
그렇다면 그녀는
아주 위생적이었거나
So either she is extremly hygenic or...
누군가가 세척을 해버렸지
Somebody did some serious
pre-Spring cleaning.
포셔 리치몬드인지 알고 싶으시면
DNA를 가져오셔야 될 거예요
If you want to know if it's Portia,
you got to get the DNA somewhere.
20년 동안 여기 살면서
I can't believe I've been in this town twenty years
리버라치 박물관이 있는지
몰랐다는 게 믿기지 않네요
and I've never seen the Liberace Museum.
우습군. 난 며칠 전에
여기 왔었는데
That's funny, I was just here
a couple days ago.
그래요?
I believe it.
우린 여기에 리버라치의
모든 의상을 비치해 놨죠
We have all of Liberace's
costumes on display here.
이 의상은 1984년 뉴올리언스
세계 박람회 때 입은 거죠
This one, for example... Worn by Mr. Liberace
in the 1984 World's Fair in New Orleans.
멋지네요
Lovely.
예전 쇼를 보신 적 있나요?
50년대의 리도 쇼 같은 거
Did you ever see one of the old shows?
The Lido in the '50's?
제가 태어나기 전인걸요
Before my time.
맞아요. 그렇군요
You weren't even born then, of course.
모든 댄서들은 다
프랑스에서 왔었죠
Every dancer was from France.
의상의 사소한 부분까지 신경
쓰는 것 자체가 정말 대단했죠
The attention to detail
in the costumes was unparalleled.
관객들은 멋지게 차려 입고 말이에요
And the audience, dressed to the nines.
그땐 지금과는 달랐죠
The town was different then.
뉴욕이나 시카고, 런던 같은
큰 도시에서는 다시 복원했죠
The other great cities. New York,
Chicago, London, they restore.
하지만 이곳엔 사라지고 없죠
But in this town, they destroy.
포셔 리치몬드의 의상을
보고 싶다고 하셨죠?
So you want to see what belonged
to Portia Richmond.
네
Yes, please.
광기의 베르지에, 1959
[Folies Bergiere; LV에서 공연한 쇼]
Folies Bergiere' 1959.
무거워 보이군
Looks heavy.
머리에 그걸 쓰고 하룻밤에
두 번 쇼에 나왔다고 생각해 보세요
Imagine that on your head,
two shows a night.
15개가 넘는 빗을 에폭시와
접착제로 고정하고 말이에요
She used over fifteen combs,
and various epoxies and glues.
머리에서 떨어지지 않도록 끼워서
못처럼 고정하는 역할을 했죠
They damn near had to drive a spike
into her head to keep it from falling off.
결국 머리가 다 뽑혀나갔죠
She lost all her hair.
DNA 천지네요
DNA heaven.
워릭!
Warrick!
엘리베이터 희생자의 소지품이야
The personal artifacts
from your elevator victim.
멋지군
Cool!
누군지 알아냈어?
You got an I.D. for me?
운전면허증으로 알아냈지
여기 사람이고
Driver's license. He's a local.
타이슨 그린이고 35세야
Tyson Green. Thirty-five.
렌즈를 끼지 않고는
운전할 수 없는 사람이고
Can't drive without corrective lenses.
그러게, 눈이 너무 나빠서
엘리베이터도 작동하지 못했군
Yeah. Too bad he wasn't
driving that elevator.
아 …. 시카고 뱅크롤
[Chicago Bankroll : 도박, 포커의 한 형태]
Hoo. A Chicago bankroll.
이 남자는 여기 사람인 걸
('시카고 돈다발'로 생각함)
This guy's not from out of town.
아냐, 용어를 말한 거야
오래된 도박 방법이지
No, that's just a term. Old school.
새우 칵테일 애피타이저, 서프 앤 터프 디너
와인 두잔, 모두 무료
Shrimp Cocktail Appetizer. Surf and Turf Dinner.
Two glasses of wine. All comped.
공짜란 말이지? 좋네
Free food, nice.
절대 공짜가 아닐걸, 날 믿어
It ain't free. Believe me.
괜찮아?
You okay?
그래, 그래...
Yeah, yeah...
이것들 본 지 오래됐군
Been a long time since I've seen these.
이봐, 워릭
Hey, Brown.
탄도분석실 바비 도슨하고
얘기를 했는데
Just talked to Bobby Dawson in ballistics.
엘리베이터에서 수거한
것을 조사했는데
He ran that .22 from the elevator.
일련번호로 보니 웨스트사이드에
사는 빈센트 모건으로 나오더군
Serial number came back Vincent
Morgan. Lives on the Westside.
- 멋지네요
- 갈까?
- Cool!
- Comin'?
이것 좀 기록해서 보관해 줄래?
Yeah, can you log these for me?
그래
Yeah.
맨디, 피해자에게서 발견한 25센트
동전에서 지문 떠냈어?
Mandy, you got any prints off
that quarter I found on the vic?
계속 하고 있어요. 하루에 한 가지
사건만을 하는 게 아니잖아요
Still working on it, Warrick.
I don't work one case a day.
빙고!
Bingo!
이거 단지 45분밖에 안 결렸는걸
Well. That only took forty-five minutes.
뭘 찾았는데?
What do you got?
패트릭 헤인즈의
주민번호를 쳤더니
A hit of Patrick Haynes'
social security number.
문제가 있더군
There's only one problem
10년 전에 죽은 8개월짜리
아이로 나온다는 거지
he's an eight-month-old
infant that died ten years ago.
같은 주민번호 맞아? 확실해?
Same social? You sure?
이거야 !
Bam. !
좋은 거야?
Something good?
그럼
Oh yeah.
해냈어, 우와, 그래
We got a match, boom. Match,
와~ 해냈다고, 우와
boom... we got a match. Boom.
그렉, 그것 좀 벗어줄래?
You wanna take that thing
off your head, Greg?
증거잖아
It's evidence!
좋아요, 선배
Cool, your jets, Cath.
당연히 증거물들은
따로 다 빼놨죠
I got all the evidence out of it. y'know?
여자 DNA였어요. 선배님도 춤출 때
이런 것을 쓰고 했나요?
It's all woman. Did you ever wear
one of these when you were dancing?
난 아무것도 안 입었었지 / 어머나!
I wore nothing but skin. / Oooh!
음... 그 이에서 나온 DNA와
I uh, compared the DNA from the tooth
이 소품 안에서 발견된
모낭 DNA와 비교 했더니
with the hair follicles found inside the headdress.
일치했어요, 반장님
I think we have a match, sir.
살인사건인 거죠
And I think we may have a homicide.
실례하겠습니다
Excuse me.
그래 제가 그걸 신고 안한
것이 위법인가요?
So, did I like, break the law
by not reporting it?
하지만 당신 집이
강도를 당했을 때
But it's a good idea that
when your house is robbed,
등록된 총기를 잃어버렸다고
신고하는 게 낫겠죠
you report that your
registered gun was stolen.
저 남자 말이 맞는 것 같아
Guy's story checks out.
강도를 당했더군 / 네, 보세요!
He was robbed. / Yeah, look!
제 아내는 애가
생기고 나서부터는
My wife. She's not real comfortable about having
집에 총 두는 걸
싫어했어요
a gun in the house ever since we had our boy.
제가 없애겠다고 말만 하고
그러지 않았거든요
And I told her that I got rid of it,
but I never did.
전 그게 살인에 쓰일 거라고
상상도 못했어요
I mean, man, the last thing I ever expected
was it'd be used in a murder.
한동안은 필요할 때마다
연락드리겠습니다
Well, we're going to keep
your name on ice for a while.
시간 내주셔서 감사합니다
Thanks for your time.
감사합니다
Hey thanks, right on.
이봐, 309번 차 끌고 와
Uh, hey! Bring up car 309.
누구도 자신의 등록된 총으로
살인을 하진 않지요
Nobody kills anybody with
their registered gun anymore.
꼭 그렇지는 않을 걸
Isn't that the truth.
경감님 / 응
Jim! / Hey!
모든 곳을 감시하고 있네
We got the whole place clocked.
헤인즈 부부를 주시하면서 말이야
Keeping an eye on the Haynes couple.
서장은 그들이 도망가는
것을 바라지 않더군
Sheriff doesn't want 'em skipping town.
그건 우리도 마찬가지죠
Neither do we.
포셔 리치몬드가 죽었다는
강한 의혹이 있어요
We have a strong suspicion
Portia Richmond is dead.
저것 봤어요?
Did you see that?
저 사람들 협잡꾼이네요
They're on the grift.
사람들 바로 앞에서
모피를 훔치는군요
She took that fur from
right under their noses.
코트를 살펴봐도 될까요?
May we check your coats?
당신들 도대체 뭐요?
부부 절도단이요?
What are you, a couple of kleptos?
전 모르는 일입니다
I don't follow.
5천 달러어치의 절도야
당신 아내가 훔친 거 아닌가?
A five thousand dollar stole
your wife stole?
당신들 뭐하는 사람들인가?
What, are you guys in business?
아만다는 그리섬 씨가 말하기 전까지
모피를 가져왔다는 걸 몰랐어요
Amanda didn't know she'd even taken it
until Mr. Grissom here told her.
꼭 그런 사람들 같군, 흠 …
Is that kind of like the guy who uh,
주머니에 센트라를 담아서 자동차
영업소를 나온 사람들 말이야
walks out of the auto mall with a
Nissan Sentra in his pocket?
제가 왜 여기 있죠? 왜요?
Why am I here? Why?
경감님, 제가 물어봐도 될까요
Jim, may I?
헤인즈 씨, 레이스 듀발에게
성폭력 여부 조사를 해봤는데
Mr. Haynes, we ran a sexual
assault kit on Lacey Duvall.
정액이 발견됐죠
We found semen.
설명해 줄래요? / 네
Can you explain that? / Yeah.
제 집사람이 여기 없으니까 …
Yeah, my wife's not here.
사실을 말할 수 있겠군요
Time to convert lies into the truth.
전 파티가 열리기 전에
레이시와 섹스를 했죠
I had sex with Lacey before the party.
DNA 샘플을 주시겠어요?
Would you mind giving us a DNA sample?
그럼요. 레이시와의 관계는
단지 성적인 관계였을 뿐이죠
No. My relationship with
Lacey was purely sexual.
멋진 섹스였죠
정말 황홀한 섹스 말이에요
It was good sex. Well, great sex.
틈만 나면 우린 했어요
Whenever we could
steal a moment, we did.
그녀는 마약과 같았어요
Well, she was like an addiction.
체액을 교환하는 거 말고도
Well, in addition to exchanging bodily fluids,
선물도 교환했었나요?
did you exchange gifts?
무슨 말씀이죠?
Whatever do you mean?
질문에나 답하게
Just answer the question.
아뇨
No.
아무것도 선물한 것 없습니다
No, I never gave her anything
그래요? 레이스 듀발의 탈의실에서
음악상자를 발견했는데
Well, we found a music box
in Lacey Duvall's dressing area
포셔 리치몬드 것이더군요
that belonged to Portia Richmond.
그걸 그녀에게 줬나요?
Did you give it to her?
정말 아니에요
Honestly, no.
그 음악상자는 포셔 거지
제 게 아니죠
Those music boxes belonged
to Portia. Not to me
하긴 레이시는 집에 들렀을 때
그것들을 가지고 싶어 하더군요
But Lacey had been by the house,
and she did admire them.
그녀가 훔쳤다는 건가?
Are you saying that she lifted it?
인간의 본성이죠
Human nature.
갖지 못하는 것을
탐내는 법 아닌가요
We always covet what we can't have.
그럼 당신은 포셔 리치몬드한테
무엇을 탐냈죠?
What did you covet from Portia Richmond?
반장님, 잠깐만요?
Grissom, can I talk to you?
도대체 일을 하자는 건가
말자는 건가?
Are you looking for work?
- 전 그냥 ….
- 문에 들어오지 말라고 써 있잖나
- I just....
- The Sign says Do not enter. Nick.
읽지도 못하나?
장님이야? 뭐야?
You can't read anymore.
Your blind? What?
- 반장님, 중요한 문젭니다
- 이게 중요한 거야!
- Grissom, this is important.
- This is important.
보통 이런 심문할 땐 기회도 한 번이고
진술을 받는 것도 한 번 밖에 없는 거야
Sometimes in these interrogations,
Nick, you get one chance, one answer.
내가 이렇게 밖에서
자네와 말다툼을 할 때
And while I'm out here
screwing around with you,
저런 인간은 자네가 들어오기 전엔 생각하지
못했던 이야기들을 꾸며낸단 말이야
he's in there thinking up an answer
that he didn't have before you walked in.
레이시 듀발의 DNA가 텍사스에서 10년 전
발생한 미결사건의 DNA와 일치해요
We matched the DNA taken from Lacey Duvall
to a "cold case" in Texas ten years ago.
그래서!?
And?
그 용의자 이름이
채드 매튜예요
The suspect's name was Chad Matthews.
CM. 단추
CM. The cufflink.
그렇군, 미안해
Okay I'm starting to forgive you.
새라가 패트릭 헤인즈의
주민번호를 조사해봤는데요
Sara ran Patrick Haynes' social.
진짜 헤인즈는
죽은 사람이에요
The real Haynes is deceased.
패트릭 헤인즈가 채드 매튜인거죠
결과적으로 채드 매튜가 도망중이고요
So Patrick Haynes is Chad Matthews,
and Chad Matthews is on the run.
제 발로 우리에게
걸어 들어왔군
And he just ran into us.
안녕하세요, 다시 뵙게 되어 반갑습니다
Good morning, it's nice to have you back.
자네는 내가 저기 안에
아침 먹으러 들어가서
Do you have any idea what the hot
topic of conversation's going to be
무슨 말을 할지 아나?
when I walk into that breakfast?
시장에 출마하시겠다고
발표하시려는 거 아닌가요?
You're announcing your
candidacy for Mayor?
눈치가 빠르구먼
That's cute.
패트릭 헤인즈는 구금 중이지
Patrick Haynes is in custody.
그가 포셔 리치몬드가
사라진 것과 관련이 있나?
Does he have anything to do with
Portia Richmond's vanishing act?
헤인즈는 다른 문제 때문에
텍사스로 송환될 예정입니다
Haynes is in lockup awaiting extradition
to Texas on an unrelated matter.
그렇다면 그 동안 우리는
포셔 리치몬드의 실종과
So in the meanwhile we're
questioning him in connection
관련해서 심문을 해야겠군
with Portia Richmond's disappearance?
서장님께 찍어야겠군요
You know I think you're gonna
get my vote for mayor.
리치몬드에 관해 뭐가 나왔나?
What've you got on Richmond?
송곳니 하나요
A canine.
개 말인가?
Her dog?
이빨이요
Her tooth.
다른 건 뭐 없고?
What about the rest of her?
계속 찾고 있습니다 / 수고하게
Still looking. / Look harder.
언론에 그녀가 죽었다고 알려진 뒤
'Cause if someone leaks it
to the press that she's dead,
그녀가 맥카렌 공항에 피부가
그을린 채 내리기라도 한다면
and then she gets off
a Lear Jet at McCarran with a tan,
우린 비난을 면치 못할 거고
자네에겐 책임을 물을 걸세
we're both going to have egg on our face.
And I'm going to hold you responsible.
포셔 리치몬드가 이 자리에
내가 있게 했고 난 그녀 편이네
Portia Richmond got me elected,
Grissom. I was at her party.
무슨 말인지 이해하겠지?
Do you see what this does to me?
증거는 좋은 와인과 같죠, 서장님
마개를 따서 바로 마셔버릴 수는 없죠
Evidence is like a fine wine, Brian.
You can't just open the bottle and drink it.
그 향을 충분히 음미해야겠죠
You've got to let it breathe.
내 여기서 분명히 말해두지
Look, I'm gonna lay this on the line
for you, right here and now.
포셔 리치몬드를 찾아내거나
그녀 살인의 동기를 찾아내게
You find me Portia Richmond or
you find me a motive for her murder.
해결될 때까지
예의 주시하겠네
Because I'm in your kitchen 'til it's solved.
편하게 지내세요
Make yourself at home.
어디 있었나?
Where've you been?
똥꼬 쑤시는 사람하고요
Proctologist.
서장이 자네를 들볶았구먼
그렇지?
Sheriff getting your ass, huh?
내가 큰 걸 물었다네
Well, I just hit mega-bucks.
오스틴 경찰 측이 채드 매튜에겐
5개의 가명이 있다더군
Austin P.D. has five aliases for Chad Matthews.
탐 쉐리던, 비첨 카운티에서 절도죄와
수표 사기 혐의로 수배 중이고
Tom Sheridan. Wanted in Beacham County.
Petty theft. Check fraud.
워너 드라이스데일, 새크라멘토에서
중절도와 차량 절도죄로 수배 중
Warner Drysdale. Wanted in Sacramento.
Grand larceny. Car theft.
시운전으로 차를 몰고 나갔다가
그대로 도망갔다더군
The guy took a car for a test drive.
Never brought it back.
작 재스퍼, 내가 이 이름들을
지어내는 게 아니네
Jock Jasper. I'm not
making these names up.
덴버에 사는 부자 미망인한테
돈을 갈취했더군
Extorted money from
a rich widow in Denver.
- 정말 바쁜 놈이군요
- 그래 게다가 계획적이지
Busy boy. / Yeah, and organized too.
덴버 경찰이 그의 기록을 보내왔네
Denver P.D. sent copies of his journals.
그 놈은 전국의 돈 많은 여자들
리스트를 가지고 있었더군
Guy kept a list of rich women
all around the country.
중요한 정보가 다 기록되어 있더군
키, 몸무게, 재산이 얼마가 되는지 등등
Logged in all their vitals. Height, weight,
how much money they have, you name it.
그 리스트에 누가 있었는지 맞혀보게
Guess who's on the list.
이름이 'ㅍ'로 시작하지 않아요?
Does your name begin with a "P"?
신용카드 사용기록에 따르면
Well, according to her credit card statement,
지중해에 간 뒤로
한 푼도 쓰지 않았더군
Portia Richmond hasn't spent a dime
since she's been in Mediterranean.
살해당한 거죠
She's dead.
글쎄, 꼭 그런 건 아닐 거야
아마 파도에 휩쓸렸는지도 모르지
Well, not necessarily. Maybe
she's been swept off her feet.
어떤 남자가 대신
내줬는지도 모르지
Yeah, some guys still like to foot the bill.
정말, 네가 어떻게 알아?
Really, how would you know?
난 여자들이 이상한 질문을 했을 때만
각자 계산하자고 하거든
Hey, I only go "Dutch"
if girls ask the wrong question.
닉, 이상한 질문이라는 게 뭐야?
And what question is that, Nick?
차가 뭔지 묻는 거라든지
What do you drive?
그건 솔직한 질문이잖아
It's an honest question.
아냐, 그게 아니지
No. No, it's not.
그 말은 자기를 먹여 살릴 수
있을 만큼 돈을 버는지 떠보는 거야
What it means is, how much money
do you make, so you can take care of me.
그렇다면 이 여자는
해당 안 되는군
Well, not this girl.
제군들 이걸봐
Boys and girls,
서명이 위조됐어
we got ourselves a forgery.
수표가 위조됐다는 건가요?
아님... 서명이?
Either that or a dimpled ballot.
글쎄, 이름은 채드로군
Well, his name is Chad.
점들을 연결해 보죠
Let's connect the dots.
무슨 말이야?
What does that mean?
내가 보여주지
Here I'll show you.
선배, 귀걸이 핀 좀 빌려줄래요?
Catherine, you wear pierced earrings. May I?
그래, 근데 ... 이거 ...
일주일 내내 끼고 있던 거라
Alright, but uh...
I've had them on for a week,
뭐가 끼어 있을지도 모르겠네
can't account for what's on it.
사인해봐 / 응
Sign your name, please. / Okay.
누구도 똑같은 모양으로
사인을 두 번 할 수 없지
Now, nobody signs their signature
exactly the same way twice.
너도 참 …. 글씨가 엉망이군
Not even you, chicken scratch.
만약 동일한 사인이 있다면
그것들 중 하나는 위조된 거지
If they do, then one of them is a forgery.
점들을 연결해서
만든 게 이거지
Here's where connecting the dots comes in.
글씨를 따라 점을 찍으면
We dot the lines and curves of the signature.
그럼 뒷장에 눌린
자국이 나타나지
Which leaves indentations on the blank page.
그리고 그 점들을 연결하면
And then you connect the dots,
그럼 증거가 나오지
확실히 일치하지 않는군
give it the evidence, but
obviously they didn't.
무섭네요
Well that's scary.
누군가를 파산시키려면
사인 하나면 된다는 게
All you need is one signature
to break somebody.
안돼 보이네요
You look terrible.
헛수고 하느라
그런 거지 뭐…
Been spinning my wheels.
이 사건을 해결
못 할 것 같아
I'm never going to solve this case.
시작하기 전부터
안 될 일이었어
It was over before it even began.
당신답지 않군요
It doesn't sound like you.
엘리베이터에서 발견된 시체에서
얻은 거라곤 수많은 지문과
I got a dead guy on a glass elevator.
With a biz-illion prints
22 구경 총탄밖에 없어
And a twenty-two caliber bullet.
사실상 추적이 불가능한 거죠
It's virtually untraceable.
살인자는 현장에 총을 버렸지
그게 무슨 뜻인지 알아?
And he left the gun at the scene.
You know what that means?
살인범이 대단한 놈이란 거죠
Hit man was a ghost.
딱 두 개만 남겨두었다고, 맞지?
Only got two things left, right.
실제론 하나죠
Make that one thing.
농담 마
You got to be kidding me.
아뇨, 상황이 더욱 안 좋아졌어요
No. It gets worse.
25센트 동전에서 지문을 떠서
조회해봤더니 죽은 사람 것이더군요
Got a print off your quarter. Ran it through
AFIS. Came back your dead man.
소름끼치네요
Pretty gruesome.
뭘 생각하고 있죠?
Want to share?
베니 비니온이 스티브 윈에게
I was just thinking about
what old man, Binion,
그가 이곳을 변화시킬 때
한말을 생각하고 있었어
told Steve Wynn when he hit town
"도박꾼들에게 도박할 변명거리를 줘라
그러면 그들이 고마워할 거다"
"Always give a gambler an excuse
to gamble, and he'll thank you for it."
죽은 사람이 도박꾼이었나요?
Was your guy a gambler?
그의 주머니에서
현금 영수증 다발과
And a bunch of cash receipts in his pockets.
여기저기의 도박장
기록지들이 있더군
Markers all over town.
한 번 빠지면 다시
빠져 나올 수 없지
Once you get to that place
there's no getting out.
누가 여기로 정했나요?
Who picked this place?
내가, 여기 어때서 …
Me. I thought it'd be nice.
좋아, 자네가 내면 되겠군
Okay, you can pick up the tab.
그럼 살인 동기에 대해
이야기 해보자고
Let's, Let us keep talking about motive.
그러죠
Lets.
전 위조된 서명이 살인에 대한
결정적 증거라고는 생각지 않아요
I don't think a forged signature
is a slam dunk for murder.
누가 반장님에게 우리 어디서
점식 먹고 있다고 말했나요?
Hey, did anyone tell Grissom
where we were having lunch?
응. 사령실에서
메시지를 남겼을 거야
Yeah, dispatch left him a message.
아마 반장은 서장이 남긴
메시지라 생각하고 무시했을 걸
Maybe he thought it was
the Sheriff and blew it off.
이보시오. 거기서 얼굴을
떼는 게 좋을 거요
Hey, you might want to take
your face away from there.
그래요? 왜죠?
Really? Why is that?
이 칠레 농어 요리 맛있네요
This Chillean seabass's wonderful.
이것도 맛있어
So is this.
좋아요. 실종된 미망인이 있고요
Okay. You got a missing widow.
그녀 침실에서 피 묻은
이가 발견됐어요
Her bloody tooth, found
in her own bedroom
그 집은 용의자 두 명이
쓰고 있고요
which is currently occupied by two moes.
용의자라, 내 생각
때문에 그런 건가?
"Moes." I'm rubbing off on you.
아니에요. 그리고 제 바다
배스 요리 먹지 마세요
No, you're not. And stay away
from my sea bass.
용의자 중 한 명은 이름이 6개나
되고 그 중 하나가 채드 매튜죠
And one of our moes has six names that
we know of, including Chad Matthews.
맞아 맞아, CM이라고
새겨진 단추를 발견했지
Right, right. And we got a cufflink
with the initials CM
수영장 바닥에서 말이야
그리고 물에 떠있던 쇼걸도
found at the bottom of a pool
along with a floating showgirl.
6개 이름을 가진 사람이
패트릭 헤인즈로 모아지는군요
Who was sleeping with six men
rolled into one Patrick Haynes.
여기, 자네가 맡은
쇼걸의 사진일세
Hey, photos of your showgirl.
내가 놓친 게 있나?
What'd I miss?
아니요, 놓쳤다는 게 아니에요
It's not what you missed.
이 부분을 빠트린 것 같아요
It's what seems to be missing.
손톱 자국요?
A fingernail?
- 좋아요, 패트릭 헤인즈
- 아니면 누구든 간에
- Okay, Patrick Haynes.
- Or whoever.
그 사람이 10년 전에 살인을 했다면
왜 쉽게 DNA를 채취하도록 뒀을까요?
Whoever, he committed a murder ten years ago,
why give up your DNA so easily?
맞아. 이름을 바꾸긴 쉬워도
DNA을 바꿀 수는 없지
Exactly. I mean, y'know, you can change
your name, but you can't change your blueprint.
- 맞아요
- 위험과 보상의 문제네요
- Right on.
- Risk versus reward.
한 여자와 자고 그 여자를 죽이고
수사망이 좁혀져 오자, 도망간 거죠
You sleep with someone, you kill her, um,
heat's on, you flee or
아님, 운에 맡겨 재수가 좋으면
건지는 거지
or you roll the dice and
maybe get your cookie.
뭘 건지는 건데?
What's the cookie?
큰돈이지
The cheese, brother.
160만 달러가 아닐까. 그날 밤
자선파티에서 모금한 돈 말이야
Maybe the money, one-point-six mil,
they raised for the charity event that night.
헤인즈 부부는 리치몬드의 계좌를 썼잖아
그리고 화상센터 관련 계좌도 말이야
See the Hayneses controlled Portia Richmond's
bank accounts, including her Burn Center account.
위조한 수표가 탈이 없는지
계속 살펴봐야 했겠지
They had to stick around
for the checks to clear.
그럼 왜 레이시 듀발을
살해한 걸까요?
So why kill Lacey Duvall?
좋은 질문이야
Excellent question.
잘 모르겠어. 하지만 레이시
듀발이 살해되지 않았다면
I don't know but if Lacey Duvall
hadn't been murdered
패트릭 헤인즈는 다시
다른 모습으로 변장했겠지
Patrick Haynes reinvents himself,
160만 달러의 부자로 살아가겠지
(Skippy : 만화 캐릭터)
becomes another Skippy in another state,
one-point-six mill richer.
네, 잠깐만요. 전 시저 샐러드
반하고 커피 한 잔만 마셨어요
Alright. Time out now.
I had a half a Caesar and a coffee.
근데 왜 제가 20불이나 내죠?
How's my end twenty bucks?
닉, 각자 계산하자는 말이지?
You want to go "Dutch", Nick?
새라, 바로 그거야
눈치 빠르네, 각자 내는 게 좋지
Excellent idea, Sara.
You're catching on. I'd love to.
경감님, 이것 좀 계산해 주세요
Uh, Brass, uh, cough it up.
닉 몫도 계산하시고요
티라 미슈도 드셨잖아요
And cover Nick's, too. You had the tera misu.
난 이래서 CSI 요원들이랑
점심 먹는 게 싫다니까
Well, I hate going out to lunch with you CSIs.
너무 많이 따져
You notice everything.
범죄 현장에서 캐서린이
발견한 손톱에서 뭔가 나왔나?
What ever happened to that fingernail
Catherine found at the crime scene?
여기 DNA 결과가 있죠
I got the DNA results right here.
먼저 온 것을 먼저 처리하거든요
패트릭 헤인즈의 DNA는 아니에요
First things first,
not a match to Patrick Haynes.s.
난 그 손톱이 남자 거라고는
생각 안했네, 그렉
I never figured a man
for the fingernail, Greg.
맞아요. 하지만 문제를 해결할
실마리를 잡은 듯 하네요
Okay, but here's where you break out
your can of creep repellent.
손톱과 정액에서 나온 DNA
대조 결과가 반만 일치해요
The fingernail and the semen share
half of DNA markers in common.
친족이라고?
Possible first-degree relatives?
부탁 좀 하세
Do me a favor.
이걸 조사해줘
Run this for me.
립글로스인가요?
누구 건데요?
What is that, lip gloss? Whose?
자네가 말해줘야지
You tell me.
네바다 주를 대신해서
사과를 드립니다
On behalf of the State of Nevada,
my apologies.
모든 혐의가 풀렸습니다
You've been cleared of all charges.
그걸 말씀하시려고
3명이나 오신건가요?
It took three of you to tell me that?
대신 텍사스 주를 대신해
당신을 체포해야겠소
But on behalf of the State of Texas,
you're under arrest.
라나 그림쇼의 살인혐의로
송환될 거요
You're being extradited for
the murder of Lana Grimshaw.
그녀와 자기는 했지만
죽이진 않았어요
I slept with her, but I didn't kill her.
레이스 듀발처럼 말이오?
Just like with Lacey Duvall?
그렇죠
Absolutely.
이제 명백해지는군
Now I see it.
뭐요, 뭘 알겠다는 거요?
What, see what?
가족 간에 닮은 것 말이요
The family resemblance.
다니와 마리
(Show 진행으로 유명한 남매)
Donny and Marie.
오빠와 동생이지
Brother and sister.
DNA 검사로 알 수 있었지
And I've got the DNA to prove it.
내가 또 알아낸 걸 말해주지
Let me tell you what else I can prove
당신 동생이 말이야
your sister,
레이시 듀발을 살해했어
killed Lacey Duvall.
'그가 나를 사랑한대'
He told me he loves me.
'이제 사랑하는 척
연기할 필요도 없지'
No more faking love. No more act.
' 그가 말했다는 게 이거야? '
' 이게 연기라고 말이야? '
Is that what he told you?
That it was an act?
확실히 연기이기는 하지
It's as real as it gets.
패트릭이 너보고 연기를
잘 못한다고 하더군
Patrick says you're small- time.
너에게 재능이 없다던 걸
You just don't have the stones to go big.
패트릭을 잘 알지도 못하면서
You don't know Patrick.
채드를 말하는 거야?
You mean, Chad?
그가 이걸 주었지
He gave me this.
다음엔 뭘까?
You know what's next.
이젠 내 차례야
It's my turn.
놀랬니?
You're surprised?
오빠 얼굴을 봐
Look at your face.
그 애를 만나기 전까진
우린 실수 없이 잘해왔잖아
You never made a mistake
until you met her.
내가 너에 대한 이야기를 해서
레이시를 죽였니?
You killed Lacey because
I told her about us?
선택의 여지가 없었어
I had no choice.
우린 파트너였잖아
We were partners.
오빤 날 속일 수 없어, 채드
You can't grift me, Chad.
누가 포셔 리치몬드에 대해서
이야기 할 거지?
Oh, who wants to tell us
about Portia Richmond?
그녀는 유럽에 있잖아요
She's in Europe.
그리스에서 요트를 타고 있어요
On a yacht. In Greece.
그래. 하긴 그녀는
연락 두절 상태지
Oh, right, she's in communicado.
구약 성경 요나서에
이런 말이 있지
Old Testament. The Book of Jonah.
'이제 하나님께서 요나를 삼킬
큰 물고기를 보내셨으니 …. '
And "Now, the Lord had arranged for
a great fish to swallow up Jonah."
이 피라냐에게 무슨 문제가 있는지 아나?
(piranha: 남미 산 식인물고기)
You know what's wrong
with this piranha though?
콜레스테롤 수치가 높더군
They've got high cholesterol.
콜레스테롤은 사람에게서만 검출되지
Cholesterol is found in humans. Not fish.
어떻게 사람의 콜레스테롤이
물고기에서 발견되는 걸까?
So how does a fish acquire
human cholesterol.
전모를 밝혀야 할 것 같지 않나?
You want to fill in the blanks?
포셔
Portia.
자네 둘은 포셔 리치몬드
살해 혐의로 체포되었네
You're both under arrest for
the murder of Portia Richmond.
타이슨 그린이란 사람 거예요
These belong to Tyson Green.
그가 빚을 못 갚을 것 같아
말해주려 왔어요
Just came to let you know
he won't be paying up.
그 사람 죽은 건가요?
What's he, dead?
네
Yeah.
또 25번 기계군
It's machine 25 again.
하루 종일 저 기계 대박이군
Been spittin' silver all day.
도박하기 좋은 날이지 않나요?
It's a good day to gamble.
라스베가스...
당신 같은 사람...
Vegas. Guy like you.
도박하러 들른 게 아니라고
말하려는 거야?!
Come on you're trying to tell me
that you didn't make a little pit stop.
자네가 자네 시간에
뭘 하든 상관 않겠네만
Look, what you do on your time
is nobody's business.
근무시간에 그러는 건
문제가 있네
What you do on my time is my business.
워릭 브라운이 내 부하를
대신 법정에 출두시켰네
Warrick Brown had one of
my guys sub for him in court.
그 시간에 도박을 하고
있었다는 증거가 있네
But I have it on good authority
that he was gambling.
워릭에겐 문제가 있어요
Warrick has a problem.
모른 척 하는 게
능사는 아니죠
Ignoring it isn't gonna make it go away.
난 다시 무너지지 않아!
I won't let you down again.
번역수정/맞춤법교정
손성봉(shon9795@nate.com)
자막제작 - 네이트 CSI 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/clubcsi)